Alexandre DuBreuil

Java Developer

Paris, France + Montreal, Canada

a +33 (0)6 27 71 46 75
c) github.com/dubreuia
y twitter.com/dubreuia
□ alexandredubreuil.com
□ contact@alexandredubreuil.com

Summary

Java developer with 10 years of experience, as a freelancer, technical lead and architect. Full stack web developer, strong background on software craftsmanship, devops and agile culture, infrastructure automation, and security. Open source maintainer, speaker in conferences, trainer and teacher on git and software factory. Language: Java, Python, Javascript, SQL

DevOps: git, Maven, Ansible, Jenkins Pipeline, Docker

Culture: Linux, DevOps, Continuous delivery Security: Threat modeling, Hashicorp Vault

Methodology: Kanban, Agile

Experience

Freelance Software Developer

(December 2018 - today) 6 months

DuBreuil Consulting (self-employed)

Paris, France

Freelance developer on full stack web development, software architecture, infrastructure automation, devops tooling, security solutions and artificial intelligence.

Software Architect

LesFurets.com

(June 2016 - October 2018) 2.5 years

Paris, France

Software Architect on a 500,000 lines web application, working on full stack refactoring, domain driven design, infrastructure automation, software factory, continuous delivery and devops tooling.

- Refactoring of the legacy insurance product domain model code and the insurance validation rules in Java.
- Modernizing of the infrastructure automation with Ansible and Docker.
- Security architecture on secrets management with Hashicorp Vault.

Technologies: Java, Docker, Ansible, Hashicorp Vault Culture: Domain Driven Design, DevOps

Technical Lead

LesFurets.com

(January 2014 - June 2016) 2.5 years

Paris, France

Technical leader of an Agile team of 5 developers responsible for the 60 web services communicating with the insurers, providing agile management, mentoring, architecture design, software development and software craftsmanship.

- Team management on the Kanban methodology, with visual management, daily stand ups, weekly One-on-One with team members.
- Team mentoring on code review and code quality, as well as pair programming.
- Development and architecture of frontend and backend services in Java.
- Development of REST and WSDL web services.
 Technologies: Java, Maven, REST, WSDL
 Culture: Kanban, Visual management, Daily stand-ups,
 One-on-One

Java EE Consultant

CGI France

(January 2010 - August 2013) 3.5 years

Paris, France

Java EE consultant on a large scale front office and back office Java application in the energy business (3,000,000 lines of code). Development, testing, delivery, training and documentation.

- Development of front-end in JSP, backend in Java and data layer in SQL.
- Development of multi-threaded algorithms, handling large datasets (1,000+ curves, millions of points) ef-
- ficiently, for the energy market on price optimisation and energy curve manipulation.
- Development of a Javascript curve visualisation component used to visualise energy curves and apply operations on them.

Technologies: Java EE, JSP, Maven, SQL, Javascript, jQuery, jQPlot



Alexandre DuBreuil

Java Developer

Paris, France + Montreal, Canada

a +33 (0)6 27 71 46 75
c) github.com/dubreuia
y twitter.com/dubreuia
m alexandredubreuil.com
⋈ contact@alexandredubreuil.com

Conferences

Hashicorp Vault and Continuous Delivery

Conference on securing your application secrets with infrastructure automation, continuous delivery and Hashicorp Vault.

• 2019/06/12 – Open R&Day @ Paris, France

(April 2019 - June 2019) 3 conferences

- 2019/04/25 JUG @ Nantes, France
- 2019/04/17 Devoxx @ Paris, France
 Tags: Hashicorp Vault, Continuous Delivery, DevOps,
 Security

Domain Object Oriented Validation (dOOv)

Conference our library, dOOv, a fluent API for type-safe domain model validation and mapping (see doov.io)

- 2018/06/20 Open R&Day @ Paris, France
- 2018/06/10 JDK.IO @ Copenhagen, Danmark
- (October 2017 June 2018) 5 conferences
- 2018/01/24 Snowcamp @ Grenobles, France

• 2018/05/09 – BGL META @ London, UK

• 2017/10/26 - Softshake @ Geneva, Switzerland Tags: dOOv, Java, Domain Driven Design

Apache Spark for Java Developers

Conference on using Apache Spark with Java.

- 2017/10/27 Softshake @ Geneva, Switzerland
- 2017/06/22 Devoxx @ Krakow, Poland
- 2017/04/19 Breizhcamp @ Rennes, France

(January 2017 - October 2017) 6 conferences

(September 2014 - June 2017) 7 conferences

- 2017/02/09 Snowcamp @ Grenoble, France
- 2017/01/31 BBL Whoz @ Paris, France
- 2017/01/24 BBL Murex @ Paris, France

Tags: Java, Apache Spark, Big Data

Continuous Merge with git-octopus

Conference on shipping code to production everyday in a feature branching environment with git-octopus.

- 2017/06/14 Open R&Day @ Paris, France
- 2016/11/07 BBL WorkIT @ Paris, France
- 2016/11/13 JUG @ Marseille, France

- 2016/06/29 BBL SG @ Paris, France
 2016/01/31 JUG @ Tours, France
- 2015/12/10 BBL Octo @ Paris, France
- 2014/11/01 AgileTour @ Rennes, France

Tags: git, DevOps, Continuous delivery

Projects

Domain Object Oriented Validation (dOOv) ★25

(September 2017 - today) 2.5 years

Maintainer of dOOv, a fluent API for type-safe bean validation and mapping. Tags: Java, Domain Driven Design

Intellij Save Action Plugin ★289

(January 2015 - today) 4 years

Creator and maintainer of an Intellij plugin that adds save actions to the IDE. Tags: Java, Intellij

Project git-octopus ★171

(November 2014 - June 2017) 3.5 years

Evangelist and committer on git-octopus, a tool enabling the continuous merge workflow. Tags: git

Climat General at Venice Art Bienale

(January 2017 - November 2017) 1 year

Generative music algorithms and sound design for the Climat General exhibit of the artist Claire Malrieux. *Tags:* NodeJS, Ableton Live

Alexandre DuBreuil

Java Developer

Paris, France + Montreal, Canada

★ +33 (0)6 27 71 46 75
♠ github.com/dubreuia
★ twitter.com/dubreuia
★ alexandredubreuil.com
★ contact@alexandredubreuil.com

Education

Pierre and Marie Curie University (Paris VI) (September 2009 - January 2010) 4 months

 ${\bf Computer~Science~Master~-~International~exchange~-~CREPUQ}$

Paris, France

International exchange student from University of Montreal.

University of Montreal

(September 2007 - January 2011) 4 years

Computer Science Baccalaureate

Montreal, Quebec

Program with 1 semester of international exchange and 3 internships of 4 months

- CGI Paris internship Java backend development (see experience).
- CGI Montreal internship Java full stack web development with Hibernate for an internal application.
- CHUM Montreal internship Java full stack web development for an internal application.

Jean-de-Brebeuf College

(September 2005 - June 2007) 2 years

DEC in science, letters and arts

Montreal, Quebec

Interests

Big music geek, listen at alexandredubreuil.com/music, also

Sports cycling, squash, climbing

Geek mechanical keyboards, gaming, vim

Music modular synthesizer, music production, DJ